# Bilal Mughal

# Telephony Engineer

Address Nairobi Kenya

**Phone** 0797686905

E-mail mughalbilal89@gmail.com

Highly motivated and experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative and user-friendly applications. I have over 1 year of experience in the software industry, working as a junior software engineer and now as a telephony engineer.

In my current role, I am responsible for providing technical support to customers and users, maintaining and troubleshooting existing telecommunications systems, and implementing new telecommunications systems work closely with a team of engineers to ensure that our applications meet the needs of our customers.

### **Skills**

MYSQL

Agile Methodology

Development Lifecycles

JavaScript framework management

Web-based software engineering

.NET development

Linux

## **Work History**

#### 2023-05 - Current

## **Telephony Engineer**

Calltronix, Nairobi

- Responsible for providing technical support to customers and users, maintaining and troubleshooting existing telecommunications systems, and implementing new telecommunications systems.
- Identified and corrected system faults to minimize operational system downtime.
- Support users in setup and configuration of telephony systems.
- Monitor telephony hardware operations to evaluate proper configuration.

#### 2022-08 - 2023-05

## **Junior Software Engineer**

Calltronix, Nairobi

Currently working on designing and improving the already in place CRMS
Recommend and execute improvements on the current systems that have
already been deployed

- Testing and evaluating new techniques that can be used to improve the current systems.
- Contributed to weekly scrum meetings with team updates.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Analyzed proposed technical solutions based on customer requirements.
- Participated in architecture, design and implementation of back-end features using php and laravel.

#### 2022-05 - 2022-10 Intern

Calltronix, nairobi

- Provided IT support to users, which included hands on remote assistance in computer set-ups and troubleshooting also answered on the spot, enquires made by users about the systems
- Monitoring the day-to-day network performance help maintain and resolve issues on LAN/WAN, VoIP.
- Responded to support requests from end-users and patiently walked individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks.
- Monitored systems in operation and quickly troubleshot errors.
- Refurbished PC systems and peripherals such as monitors, networking equipment, printers, and more.
- Linked computers to network and peripheral equipment.
- Tested and installed motherboards, processors, and graphics cards on desktops and laptops for corporate staff.

#### 2021-06 - 2021-07 Intern

Calltronix, Nairobi

- Trained new system users and employees to promote useful system knowledge of the new telephony system
- Helped solve issues any users were having with the telephony system.
- Delivered assistance and support for team-based IT projects.
- Supported team needs with research and problem-solving abilities.

#### **Education**

2020-04 - 2022-04 Bachelor of Science: Computing

University of Greenwich - UK

2019-08 - 2020-11 BTEC Nationals: Computing

Oshwal College - Nairobi

2018-01 - 2019-04 BTEC Level 3 : IT

Oshwal College

computing International level

2015-01 - 2018-09 High School Diploma

## **Additional Information**

• CERTIFICATES, ICDL August, 2019 - November, 2019 International Certificate of Digital Literacy

## Languages

English

Punjabi

## **Certifications**

2020-05

**ICDL** 

## **Interests**

Programming

Gamming

Motorsports